<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming Tasks on EMF Adapter Tutorial</title>
    <link>http://sebfisch.github.io/emf-adapter-tutorial/docs/programming_tasks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming Tasks on EMF Adapter Tutorial</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://sebfisch.github.io/emf-adapter-tutorial/docs/programming_tasks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Typed Adapters</title>
      <link>http://sebfisch.github.io/emf-adapter-tutorial/docs/programming_tasks/typed_adapters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sebfisch.github.io/emf-adapter-tutorial/docs/programming_tasks/typed_adapters/</guid>
      <description>Step 4: Refactoring the adapters In order to work on this task, check out the code for the third step from the git repository or download the corresponding zip file.
git checkout -b step3 step3-object-adapter-v1  This step contains the base class ObjectAdapter discussed previously.
Refactor the classes FieldAccess, FieldUi and BoardUi to extend the ObjectAdapter class instead of implementing the Adapter interface directly.
 Adjust the constructors of all adapters to call the superclass constructor with the correct class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winning Check</title>
      <link>http://sebfisch.github.io/emf-adapter-tutorial/docs/programming_tasks/winning_check/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sebfisch.github.io/emf-adapter-tutorial/docs/programming_tasks/winning_check/</guid>
      <description>Step 5: Implementing the winning condition In order to work on this task, check out the code for the fourth step from the git repository or download the corresponding zip file.
git checkout -b step4 step4-typed-adapters-v1  This step contains the solution for the previous task.
If you looked closely, you might have noticed that the animation of the app shown in the beginning was different from the version implemented so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Escape Restart</title>
      <link>http://sebfisch.github.io/emf-adapter-tutorial/docs/programming_tasks/escape_restart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sebfisch.github.io/emf-adapter-tutorial/docs/programming_tasks/escape_restart/</guid>
      <description>Step 6: Implementing restart functionality In order to work on this task, check out the code for the fifth step from the git repository or download the corresponding zip file.
git checkout -b step5 step5-winning-check-v2  This step contains the solutions for the previous tasks.
To avoid having to reopen the app after every game, it would be useful to be able to restart games. Implement the possibility to restart games by pressing the escape key.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>